# **BUSHRA JAVED**



Jersey City, NJ 07302

Bushrazafar6789@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bushra-javed

https://bushra-javed.github.io/bushraprofile/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Very enthusiastic teacher who is certified to teach computer science to high school students. With highly developed computer skills and in-depth experience using technology, in the class room, to maximize the learning experience. Adept at developing interactive lesson plans maintaining a safe and clean lab and helping students with specialized projects. I worked closely to assist all types of student learners with physical and learning disabilities, who benefited from my assistance in the classroom environment.

# **EXPERIENCE:**

# **Teacher Aide**

### Frank R. Conwell Middle School - M.S. 4 Jersey City NJ

## Sep 2019-Present

- Familiarized myself with my student IEP's, psych evaluation, diagnosis and all background information to better aide and support the child.
- Collaborated with assigned dropout prevention teacher to modify and customize lessons and activities for students.
- Worked individually with struggling students to give feedback to teacher.
- Assisted teacher in maintaining an environment conducive to learning.
- Reinforced learning of materials or skills initially introduced by the teacher
- Practiced positive reinforcement to student when following instruction
- Reported on student progress, behavior, and social skills to parent
- Volunteered in 5th-8th Grade classes to gain practical experience in computer.

# **Front-End Developer**

#### Soleeva

#### May 2016-Mar 2019

- Involved in developing the User Interactive web pages in a professional manner using web technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax and JSON
- Developed client-side form validation using JavaScript and JQuery
- Created new HTML landing pages using output files from the creative design department
- Responsible for development of websites from scratch
- Tested and debugging pages for cross-browser and screen resolution compatibility

# **Computer Science Teacher**

#### Women's institute of Science and Humanities

#### Aug 2003-Sep 2011

- Responsible for developing interactive and interesting lesson plans based on approved curriculum
- Prepare and deliver lectures to high school students on topics such as algorithms, programming, data structures, and software design
- Evaluate and graded students' class work, laboratory work, assignments, and papers
- Developed curriculum for Computer Applications Class and delivered lessons via the Internet and traditional methods

- Teach web Development using HTML5, CSS ,Bootstrap, JQuery , and JavaScript
- Engaged students and parents to improve academic performance
- Head the Examination Department for administering exams and compiling result
- Schedule and work with students individually and in small groups to review and reinforce learning, complete assignments and improve overall performance
- Trained teachers to use new application software adopted by the WISH

### **CERTIFICATION:**

# **New Jersey Education Department Certifications**

- **Endorsement:** Teacher of Computer Science Technology
- **CE:** Certification of Eligibility Type 4148
- **Issued Date:**12/2019

# **EDUCATION:**

# **Master of Science Cyber Security and Privacy**

**Present** 

**New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT)** 

- Network Protocols Security
- Security and Privacy in Computer Systems
- Cryptography and Security

# **Alternate Route Teacher Preparation Programs**

Sep 2019-present

Brook dale Community College in Lincroft, NJ

• **CE:** Certification of Eligibility-code 4148

### **Bachelors of Science**

The National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences (NUCES)

- Computer Science
- Statistics
- Mathematics

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

# **Application Software:**

- MS Word ,MS Excel, MS Power point, MS Access, MS Visio
- Internet Technologies: web searching ,email, online resources ,Google class room, online teaching resources
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, SASS, JQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap